<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: jQuery | Steven Sun's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://shpeacelover.github.io/blog/categories/jquery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://shpeacelover.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-10T12:17:46+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://shpeacelover.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Steven Sun]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jquery Enlightenment Study Notes 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://shpeacelover.github.io/blog/2014/02/19/jquery-enlightenment-study-notes/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-19T20:14:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://shpeacelover.github.io/blog/2014/02/19/jquery-enlightenment-study-notes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ol>
<li>The central concept behind jQuery is, &ldquo;find something, do something.&rdquo; More specifically, select DOM element(s) from an HTML document and then do something with them using jQuery methods.</li>
<li>Also we can extend the concept behind jQuery to include,  first creating something new, selecting it, then doing something with it.</li>
<li>Executing code when the DOM is ready, but before window.onload.</li>
<li>Make sure all stylesheets are included before your jQuery code. Doing so will make sure all the elements in the DOM are correctly rendered before jQuery begins executing code.</li>
<li>Typically we do not want to wait for the window.onload event. That is the point of using a custom event like ready() that will execute code before window loads, but after the DOM is ready to be traversed and manipulated.</li>
<li>In fact, placing all JavaScript code at the bottom of a page is a proven performance strategy.</li>
<li>When attaching events to DOM elements contained in a wrapper set, the keyword this can be used to refer to the current DOM element invoking the event.</li>
<li>$(&lsquo;a&rsquo;).get(0).title = &lsquo;jQuery.com&rsquo;; found become this: $(&lsquo;a&rsquo;)[0].title = &lsquo;jQuery.com&rsquo;; Both allow access to the actual DOM element. For the square bracket notation, it i</li>
<li>s faster because it uses native JavaScript to retrieve the element from an array, instead of passing it to a method.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
